Guide to the Douglas W. Rae Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Douglas W. Rae papers
1988-1991
MS 1833
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(6 boxes)
The Douglas W. Rae papers consist of interviews of members of the Howard family conducted from 1988 and 1989. The interviews document the social and economic experiences of an extended African American family in New Haven from the 1950s to the 1980s. The papers also include account books from Rae's tenure as chief administrative officer of the city of New Haven, Connecticut, from 1990 to 1991 which contain notes, reports, meeting minutes and daily memoranda.
Rae, Douglas W.
Custodial History
Gift of Douglas W. Rae, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Douglas Whiting Rae (b. 1939) is the Richard S. Ely Professor of Political Science and Management at Yale University. A political scientist and member of the Yale faculty since 1967, he took leave in 1990 and 1991 to serve as chief administrative officer of the City of New Haven. A fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and a former Guggenheim Fellow, Professor Rae has been a consultant for the Parliament of Spain, the Italian Christian Democratic Party, and the BBC. He has served as president of Leeway, Inc., a nonprofit corporation serving AIDS patients. Rae's research interests include urban development, urban poverty, and regionalization. His latest book, City: Urbanism and Its End (Yale University Press), was published in the fall of 2003.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in two series: Series I: Howard Family Interviews, 1988-1989 and Series II: New Haven Chief Administrative Officer Record Books, 1990-1991
Scope and Contents
The Douglas W. Rae papers consist of interviews of members of the Howard family conducted from 1988 and 1989. The interviews document the social and economic experiences of an extended African American family in New Haven from the 1950s to the 1980s. The papers also include account books from Rae's tenure as chief administrative officer of the city of New Haven, Connecticut, from 1990 to 1991 which contain notes, reports, meeting minutes and daily memoranda.
African Americans -- Economic conditions; African Americans -- Social conditions; City planning -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Rae, Douglas W.
- Howard Family Interviews, 1988-1989; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Interview transcripts. Volumes 2, 5, 8-10 missing.
  - List of interviews, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hall, Peter (#3 and #16), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Howard, Lowell (#1), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Howard, Ricky (#11 and #35), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Howard, Arwildia (# 4, #6, and #15), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Howard, Arwildia and Pareto, Jim (#S-4), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Howard, Arwildia and Family (#25 [C]), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Howard, Arwildia and Wembley, Mary (#8, #8b and #9a), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Howard, Arwildia and Yvette (#9b), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Howard, Arwildia and Howard, Clinton (son) (# 26 [A, B, and C]), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Howard, Connie (#19, #20, #21 and #36), 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Watson, Betty (#S-1), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Halperin, Andrew (#S-5), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Howard Home Auction (#S-7), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Goodnow, Karen (#S-11), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rowe, Missy (#S-12), Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - East Rock High School Teachers, 1989
    - Joyner, Dale (#S-9), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Patton, Joyce (#S-8), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fineman and Ricciardi (#S-10), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mr. Runzo (#S-14), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- New Haven Chief Administrative Officer Record Books, 1990-1991; Series II
  - Volumes 1-5, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Volumes 6-10, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Volumes 11-14, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - Volumes 15-17, 1991 (Box 6)